<Document>
# General Procedures Intro
This handles the day-to-day operation of the [bold][color=#004d75]Security Department[/bold][/color], and how all roles within should act under nominal conditions.
For more specific, threat-based proceedures see:

[bold][textlink="Security Almanac" link="security-almanac"][/bold]

[bold][textlink="Alert Level Procedures" link="security-alert-level-procedures"][/bold]

## General Procedures

- Weapons must remain holstered at all times, unless in active pursuit of a suspect. 

[bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] or higher is an exception to this rule.

[bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] must make a reasonable attempt at bringing in suspects without detainment. 
This can be waived if the suspect is:
- A flight risk.
- Has fled already.
- Uncooperative.
- An active threat to [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] or individuals around them.
- Marked as “Arrest-on-Sight (AoS)” with reason.
- Actively committing a crime within view of the [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color].

A reasonable attempt is defined as stating the reason the individual is under arrest and requesting them to follow the arresting officer to [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color]. 
Wordlessly detaining an individual is against SoP and may be considered Excessive Force, unless valid cause is provided.

The blame for Individuals incorrectly marked as AoS, or KoS (Kill on Sight) falls on the individual who has called out the order, 
or assigned the tag to the suspect in the criminal records computer. Not the [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] acting on this order.

An active threat is defined as brandishing a weapon or actively commiting/has committed a violent crime.

Suspected [bold][color=cyan]Changelings[/color][/bold], as per the Almenac, may be detained for the Officer’s safety regardless of this rule.

- [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] may request entry to a department within reason, if there is sufficient evidence of a crime being committed behind locked doors, 
or are actively in pursuit of a suspect. Otherwise they will need a Warrant to perform a search of the department.

[bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] or higher is an exception to this rule, and [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] may force their way into a department if deemed necessary. 

-[bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] must be clearly identifiable at all times as a member of [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color].

While most deem it unprofessional, flip-flops with your [bold][color=#004d75]Security Uniform[/bold][/color] (or other such combinations) is still permitted so long as you are clearly recognizable 
as [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color]. 

Undercover operations are an exception to this rule, and can only be permitted by the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Head of Security[/bold][/color]. 
Individuals initially refusing to comply with orders must be given leeway as long as you are not recognizable as [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color]. 

[bold][color=#004d75]Detectives[/bold][/color] are exempt from this rule as well, so long as they get verbal confirmation from the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Head of Security[/bold][/color] ahead of time.

-[bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] are required to hand over any SoP inappropriate equipment if the Alert Level has been changed with valid reason. 

If it has shifted from [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] to [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color], a grace period of five minutes is given. 
If it is [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] or higher to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color], or to [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color], it is extended to ten minutes.

After the grace period is over, members of [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] will be in violation of SoP if they are not carrying code-appropriate equipment.

-Any sentencing exceeding 15 minutes must be handled by the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Head of Security[/bold][/color] or the [bold][color=#00527d]Warden[/bold][/color].
</Document>